时间轴: Gelula/SDI 英文字幕: Gelula/SDI 中文字幕: sequix
Timeline by Gelula/SDI; English Subtitles by Gelula/SDI; Chinese Subtitles by sequix
- 你好埃迪 - 你好本
- Hello, Eddie. - Hello, Ben
出了什么事
What gives
我们正在寻找几个越狱的印第安人
We're looking for a couple of Indians broke out of jail
穿着显眼衬衫的年轻人
Young bucks in fancy shirts
如果你看到他们 给我在棕榈林的办公室打电话
If you see anything of them, phone my office at Palm Grove
那些印第安人一定来自这里 他们离不开家
Those Indians they looking for must be from around here. They always head for home
恋家的基・拉戈岛人
Home being Key Largo
想要点什么 杰克
Want something, Jack
坦普尔先生在吗
Mr.Temple around
他不在这里 酒店关了
He ain't here. Hotel is closed
他什么时候回来
When will he be back
我不知道
I don't know
来杯啤酒
Have a beer
- 酒吧关了 - 关了
- The bar is closed. - That's right
我告诉过你 不是吗？酒店关门了
I told you, didn't l? Hotel's closed
在夏天 一切都关了
In the summer, everything's closed
给他喝一杯
Give him a drink
你听到我说的话了！给他喝一杯
You heard me! Give him a drink
你说啤酒
You said beer
谢谢
Thank you
别客气
Think nothing of it
外围的 Bargain Lass 跑得非常快 非常卖力
Bargain Lass on the outside is running very fast and very hard
来吧 Lady Bountiful
Come on, Lady Bountiful
加油 Lady Bountiful
加油
Come on
就凭这个能选他们吗？我可以选还是不能
How's that for picking them? Can I pick them or can't I
那是他
That's him
我给他带上去
I'll take it up
如果他想要你 他会派人来找你
If he wants you, he'll send for you
我喜欢 Fancy Free
I like Fancy Free
有54公斤重
Carrying 118 pounds
这重量很大 你觉得呢
That's a lot of weight. What do you think
Fancy Free
- 你玩马？- 不
- You play the ponies? - No
-为什么不呢？- 没有那钱
- Why not? - I haven't the money
安吉尔 给这位绅士再来一杯啤酒
Angel, another beer for the gentleman
我玩长线游戏
I play the long shots
投注最喜欢的马 你会赢什么
Betting on a favorite, what do you win
当一匹我投注的马得胜 我会得到更多
When a horse comes in for me, he pays plenty
比如 Fancy Free
Take Fancy Free
晨报赔率12比1
"Morning Line, 12-1"
这太荒谬了
That's ridiculous
他应该是4比1 甚至更少 看看它的出身
He should be 4-1 , even less. Look at that breeding
父从 Chance Play，出身于奥马哈的牧马场
"By Chance Play, out of Misconstrue by Omaha. "
他没有赢过11赛道比赛 没错
He hasn't won in 11 starts, true
但他已经两次险些得胜 今天他参加了一场3000美金奖比赛 应该是小菜一碟
But he's been twice on the money and today he's running a $3000 claiming race. Ought to be a cinch
是吗
Yes
你叫什么名字
What's your name
麦克劳德 弗兰克 父从约翰 出身海伦
McCloud. Frank. By John, out of Helen
我姓唐
I'm Miss Dawn
盖伊・唐
Miss Gaye Dawn
你 他想要你
You. He wants you
请原谅我
Please excuse me
那是谁
Who's that
- 我不知道 - 他想要什么
- I don't know. - What's he want
老人坦普尔
Old man Temple
听着 先生 如果你想住这里 酒店已经关门了
Look, mister, if you're thinking of putting up here, the hotel's closed
- 下个月前不会开放 - 你为什么在这
- Won't be open for another month. - Why are you here
- 我们是客人 - 但你说..
- We're guests. - But you said..
我们在这是有特殊安排
We're here by special arrangement
我不打算留下来 我只是想见见坦普尔先生
I don't plan to stay. I just wanna see Mr.Temple
哦 好吧 你为什么不这么说
Oh, well, why didn't you say so
他在船库那边
He's out by the boathouse
坦普尔先生
Mr.Temple
我叫麦克劳德 弗兰克・麦克劳德
My name's McCloud. Frank McCloud
麦克劳德 嗯
McCloud, huh
不是麦克劳德少校吧
Not Major McCloud
是的 先生
Yes, sir
诺拉
Nora
诺拉！诺拉
Nora! Nora
过来！你什么时候到的
Come here! When did you get here
几分钟前 我正在去基・韦斯特的路上
A few minutes ago. I'm on my way to Key West
你坐公共汽车来了吗？我看到它停下来了
Did you come on the bus? I saw it stop
嘿 诺拉
Hey, Nora
快点
Hurry up
过来
Come here
看看谁来了
Look who's here
这是乔治的妻子
This is George's wife
我是弗兰克・麦克劳德少校
This is Major Frank McCloud
你好吗？坦普尔女士
How do you do? Mrs.Temple
你丈夫和我在海外一起从军
Your husband and I were in the same outfit overseas
就好像她不知道一样
As if she didn't know
少校 我给你写了一封信到圣・路易斯
I wrote you a letter, major, to St. Louis
信被遣返之前 被送到了波特兰、圣・保罗和孟菲斯
It was sent on to Portland, St.Paul and Memphis before it came back
- 以前来过这里吗？- 不 先生
- Ever been down here before? - No, sir
乔治是对的
George was right
弗洛里达群岛与我见过的任何地方都不一样 而且更热
The Keys are different than anything I've seen. And hotter
不要期望它在十一月前变凉快
Don't look for it to get any cooler before November
温度计将下降到大约38摄氏度
The thermometer will go down to about 100
沙蝇和蚊子那时会消失
The sand flies and mosquitoes will disappear
从那时开始的大约三个月 弗洛里达群岛才适合居民居住
It'll be right livable for about three months on the Keys
游客除外
Except for tourists
- 那黑凯撒的岩石呢？- 你怎么知道的
- That Black Caesar's Rock? - How'd you know
对于没来过这里的人 我对这些群岛了解很多
For one who's never been here, I know a lot about these Keys
他们是乔治最喜欢的话题
They were a favorite subject with George
他曾经在那里挖掘海盗黄金
He used to dig for pirate gold right over there
他从未失去寻找黑胡子宝藏的希望
He never lost hope of finding Blackbeard's own treasure
他一定挖了上万个洞
He must've dug 10,000 holes
- 找到什么了吗？- 哦 当然
- Ever find anything? - Oh, sure
盐水 每次都是
Salt water, every time
你会和我们在一起多久
How long will you be with us
- 一个小时左右 - 一小时
- An hour or so. - An hour
你可以腾出更多时间 我们有很多话要谈
You can spare more time than that. We got a lot to talk about
- 你想聊多久就聊多久 - 那你得在这过夜了
- I'll talk as long as you like. - Then you'll stay overnight
他可以住乔治的房间
He can have George's room
是的 爸爸
Yes, Dad
- 我可以帮你吗？- 如果你愿意的话
- May I help you? - If you will
下午好 坦普尔夫人
Afternoon, Mrs.Temple
坦普尔先生 有奥西奥拉兄弟的消息吗
Mr.Temple. Any news of the Osceola brothers
哦 对不起 本
Oh, I'm sorry, Ben
我想让你见见我儿子的指挥官 麦克劳德少校
I want you to meet my son's commanding officer, Major McCloud
- 你好吗？- 警官本·韦德 索耶
- How do you do? - Officer Ben Wade. Sawyer
如果你不介意的话 坦普尔先生 我们想四处看看
If you don't mind, Mr,Temple, we'd like to have a look around
你找不到那些印第安人 因为他们不在这里
You won't find those Indians, 'cause they ain't here
也许他们在红树林沼泽中 或许
Maybe they're in the mangrove swamps. Maybe
或者 如果你想下水 你可能会找到他们
Or maybe if you wanna go wading, you might find them
但如果我是你 我会省去自己的麻烦
But if I was you, I'd save myself the trouble
毫无疑问 他们会在天亮前自首
No doubt they'll give themselves up before morning
他们确实应该这样做 这是事实 坦普尔先生
They sure enough ought to. That's a fact, Mr.Temple
他们在狱外的时间越长 他们的处境就越艰难
The longer they stay at large, the tougher it'll be on them
愚蠢的印第安人 再坐30天牢就可以自由了
Fool Indians. 30 days to do and they bust out
印第安人坐牢30天像其它人坐牢30年
Thirty days in jail for an Indian is like 30 years for somebody else
不管怎样 我想四处看看
Anyway, I'd like to have a look around
克莱德 如果坦普尔先生说他们不在这里 那他们就不在这里
Clyde, if Mr.Temple says they ain't here, they ain't
他的话对我已经足够了 对你也应该足够了
His word's good enough for me and it ought to be good enough for you
抱歉打扰了 坦普尔先生 来吧 克莱德
Sorry to bother, Mr.Temple. Come on, Clyde
那两个兄弟和我的儿子乔治一起长大
Those two brothers and my boy, George, grew up together
他们没有害处
There's no harm in them
他们刚去了棕榈林 变得有点傲慢 开始为印第安人夺回佛罗里达
They just went to Palm Grove and got a little snootful and started to take Florida back for the Indians
也非常接近成功
Came mighty near succeeding too
我发话让他们进来自首
I sent word for them to come in and give themselves up
并不是说我知道他们在哪里 你明白的
Not that I'm supposed to know where they are, you understand
少校 我想让你见见...
Major, I want you to meet Mr..
- 巴斯 - 加西亚
- Bass - Garcia
我们见过面
We've already met
我儿子在海外的指挥官
My son's commanding officer overseas
他们一起参加了意大利战役
They were in the ltalian campaign together
从萨勒诺到卡西诺
From Salerno to Cassino
我的儿子乔治在卡西诺遇难
My boy, George, was killed in Cassino
发生什么了
What's going on here
没什么 坦普尔先生
Nothing, Mr.Temple
她怎么了
What's the matter with her
- 诺拉？诺拉！-是的 父亲
- Nora? Nora! - Yes, Father
那个女孩怎么了？她受伤了
What aithat girl? She hurt
喝太多酒了 仅此而已 坦普尔先生
Case of one too many, that's all Mr.Temple
听着！如果你们不能守规矩 你们就得离开
Look here! if you people can't behave yourselves, you gotta leave
你为什么打她
What did you hit her for
你得知道 他是个酒鬼
I'll let you in on something. She's a lush
几杯之后 她会看到幻觉
After she bends the elbow a few times, she sees things
老鼠 蟑螂 蛇 蝙蝠之类的
Rats, roaches, snakes, bats, you know
给她一巴掌是唯一让她恢复的方法
A sock in the kisser is the only thing that'll bring her out of it
你的房间准备好了 少校
Your room's ready, major
他们来这里多久了
How long have they been here
刚才那人克里和那个女人最先来的
That one, Curly, and the woman showed up first
爸爸坦普尔说我们关门了 但他要包场一周
Dad Temple told them we were closed but he offered to rent the whole hotel for a week
钱太多了 爸爸无法拒绝
It was so much money, Dad couldn't afford to turn it down
布朗先生和其他人 四天前乘坐那艘大船到的
Mr.Brown and the others arrived in that big boat four days ago
哪个是布朗
Which one is Brown
他在11号房间 除了晚上从不出来
He's in number 11. Never comes out except at night
他长什么样
What's he like
他是个女性杀手 或者他自己这么觉得
He's a lady-killer, or thinks so
我猜是富人 他一动手指 其他人就跳了起来
Rich, I guess. The others jump when he lifts a finger
在这种高温下 他们的出现不合时宜
Out of season in this heat
为什么他们决定在基・拉戈岛住下来
Why would they decide to sit down on Key Largo
他们今晚或明天离开这里
They'll be leaving here tonight or tomorrow
少校
Major
乔治死时你在他身边吗
Were you with George when he died
在
Yes
他很痛苦吗
Was he in very much pain
他从来不知道是什么击中了他
He never knew what hit him
我担心他可能会受苦
I was afraid he might have suffered
准备好后到爸爸的房间来 少校
Come down to Dad's room when you're ready, Major
对不起
Excuse me
在这过夜
Staying the night, huh
我是克里・霍夫
I'm Curly Hoff
我听说你在意大利和坦普尔老人的儿子在一起
I heard how you were with old man Temple's son in ltaly
那孩子中弹了 是吧
The kid got it, huh
太糟了
Too bad
希望你没有生气 我们那样对待你
I hope you didn't take offense the way we handled you downstairs
图茨和我当时状态不好
You caught Toots and me at a bad time
我们准备咬掉任何人的头
We were ready to bite anybody's head off
尤其是某个金发的
Especially a certain blond's
我们五人来到这钓深海鱼
Five of us come down here for the deep-sea fishing
一路从密尔沃基出发
All the way from Milwaukee
一年多来 我们一直计划来这里大展拳脚
More than a year, we'd been planning to come down here and fish our brains out
然后发生什么了？一个人带来了一个金发女郎
So what happens? One guy brings a blond
还是在我们所有人都发誓不带女人之后
And after we all swore up and down, no dames
但他必须带她来 这家伙
But he's gotta bring her, this guy
她不是喝醉哭闹 就是宿醉吵架
If she isn't drunk and crying, she's got a hangover and arguing
一分钟前她对你很生气 不跟你说话
One minute she gets sore at you and won't talk
下一分钟她又要为你表演 当着他男人的面
Next she's making a play for you right in front of the guy
然后他对我们生气 注意 不是对她
And he gets sore at us, mind you, not her
一切都被破坏了 包括我们的脾气
Everything's spoiled, including our dispositions
我们花了这么多钱 为了什么
It's cost us all this dough, and for what
世界上最糟糕的时期
The world's worst time
我问你 你能怪我们粗鲁吗
I ask you, can you blame us for getting rude
- 我不怪你 - 喝一杯怎么样
- I don't blame you. - How about a little drink, pal
现在不行 谢谢
Not right now, thanks
拉戈酒店
Hotel Largo
喝吧 只是为表明我们间没有难过的感觉
Come on, Just to show there's no hard feelings
不了 谢谢
No, thank you
非常感谢
Oh, Thank you very much
- 暴风雨警报了 - 那是什么意思
- Storm signaare up. - What's that mean
飓风要来了
Hurricane's on its way
明白我的意思了吗？还要来飓风
See what I mean? Hurricanes yet
爸爸在这里 少校
Dad's in here, major
坐下 少校
Sit down, major
战争结束了 坦普尔先生 我不再是少校了
The war's over, Mr.Temple. I'm not a major anymore
我知道那些去打仗的人不喜欢谈论战争 我也不喜欢强加给你
I know the men that went don't like talking about the war and I don't like imposing on you
但是军队的这封信是我们掌握的唯一事实
But this letter here from the War Department is the only facts we have
它让我们对一些事情一无所知
And it leaves us in the dark about a few things
我会告诉你我所知道的一切 坦普尔先生
I'll tell you everything I know, Mr.Temple
你愿意吗 弗兰克？你会吗
Will you, Frank? Will you
我将不胜感激
I'd be most grateful
- 我应该从哪里开始？- 都可以
- Where shall I start? - Anywhere
他从头到尾都是一名好士兵
He was a good soldier from start to finish
你会感到自豪 就像他团里的每个人一样
You'd have been proud like every man in his regiment was
- 是吗 弗兰克？- 有充分的理由
- Were they, Frank? - With good reason
这不仅仅是履行职责的问题
It wasn't just a matter of doing his duty
他一直想做更多
He was always looking for a way to do more
也真的做了更多
And finding it
乔治是天生的英雄
George was a born hero
他无法想象自己的死亡 只害怕耻辱
He couldn't imagine his death. Only dishonor
是的 当然是的
No, of course not
他能坚持到卡西诺真是个奇迹
It's a wonder he lasted till Cassino
当你像乔治那样相信时 死亡就不是很重要了
When you believe like George believed, dying isn't very important
有一次在圣・彼得城外 乔治和其他几人建立了一个观察哨
Once, outside San Pietro, George and a couple others established an forward observation post
他们被直接击中 一些人被杀
They got a direct hit, and the others were killed
岗哨留给了乔治
That left it up to George
三天三夜他一直保持清醒 指挥我们开火
Three days and three nights he stayed awake directing our fire
大部分时间 我都在电话的另一端
Most of that time, I was on the other end of the line
为了让自己保持清醒 他对着电话说话
To keep himself awake, he talked into the phone
一直在谈论
Talked and talked
他的大部分谈话都是关于你们两个的
Most of his talk was about you two
你会惊讶于我对你们俩的了解如此之多
You'd be surprised how much I know about you both
例如 在你的结婚戒指内有一个铭文
For instance, inside your wedding ring there's an inscription
永远
Evermore
没错
That's right
还有你 坦普尔先生
And you, Mr.Temple
你还记得告诉乔治上唇的空洞是什么吗
Do you remember telling George what this hollow is above the upper lip
在他出生之前 你说他知道生与死的所有秘密
Before he was born, you said he knew all the secrets of life and death
然后在他出生时 一位天使来把他的手指放在这里
And then at his birth, an angel came and put his finger right here
封住了他的嘴唇
And sealed his lips
我记得
I remember that
当我给他讲那个童话故事时 他不过7岁
He couldn't have been more than 7 years old when I told him that fairy story
他被埋葬的地方怎么样
What's it like where he's buried
刚好穿过斜坡
Just crosses on a slope
高处是教堂的遗迹
High up, there's what's left of a church
你可以从乔治所在的地方看到一条河
You can see a river from where George is
我想去那个地方看看
I'd like to pay a visit to that place
是的 我愿意
Yep, I would
诺拉 也许我们会这样做
Nora, maybe we'll do just that
去意大利看看乔治埋葬的地方
Go to ltaly and see where George is buried
它属于我们 不是吗？那块地
It belongs to us, don't it? That plot of ground
我非常感谢你 弗兰克
I'm very grateful to you, Frank
谢谢
Thank you
有暴风雨警告 爸爸
There was a storm warning, Dad
你最好去看看船
You better see to the boat
是什么让你来到这里 弗兰克
What brought you down here, Frank
以为我可以在海上谋生
Thought I might make my living on the sea
- 打算做什么？- 都可以 希望在渔船上
- Doing what? - Doesn't matter. Hand on a fishing boat
陆地上的生活对我来说太复杂了
Life on land's become too complicated for my taste
战前你做什么工作
What'd you do before the war for pay
我是一家报纸的发行经理
I was circulation manager for a newspaper
- 你再也没有回到报社？- 我无法坚持下去
- You never went back to it? - I couldn't stick it
自报纸以来我做了很多工作
I've done lots since the paper
出租车司机 服务员 任何可以赚钱的活
Driving taxis, waiting on tables. Anything to make a dollar
包括日工
Including day labor
有点辛苦啊
Getting kind of rough
少校 这是菲尼先生
Major, this is Mr.Feeney
- 你好 - 你好吗
- Hi, pal. - How do you do
你船尾的地面固定怎样
How's your ground tackle off the stern
很稳
Plenty heavy
那么我们最好加倍这些绳索
Then we'd just better double up on these bowlines
你是从哪里学的船
Where'd you learn about boats
我的初恋情人是一艘船
My first sweetheart was a boat
你觉得那艘船怎么样
How do you like that boat
不错 这飓风来了 她应该远离那些暗礁
Nice. She should be away from those reefs with this blow coming
是这样吗
That so
把它放在那边的那个桩上
Put that on that piling over there
查理
Charlie
来自小龙虾岛的查理・维诺卡和他的家人
Charlie Wenoka and his family from Crawfish island
维诺卡家族是皇室 查理是塞米诺尔民族的王子
The Wenokas are royalty. Charlie's a prince of the Seminole nation.
他的祖先位于是众神之列
His ancestors go back to the gods
他在海边卖贝壳
He selseashells by the seashore
你好 奥乔比妈妈
Hello, Mama Ochobee
这里的每个印第安人都是奥乔比妈妈的后裔
Every Indian here is a descendent of Mama Ochobee
她承认自己108岁 但她有一个112岁的孩子
She admits to being 108 years old. But she has a son who's 112
我们怀疑妈妈没有说出她年龄的真相
We suspect Mama doesn't tell the truth about her age
新丈夫？不 妈妈 不是新丈夫
Him new husband? No, Mama. Not new husband
你有烟吗
You got cigarette
相当大的飓风要来了
Pretty big blow coming
印第安人总是知道 不要问他们怎么知道的 他们就是知道
Indians always know. Don't ask me how, but they do
还会有更多印第安人 他们从最远的基・马特库姆贝来到我们这里
More will be along. They come to us from as far as Matecumbe Key
这一个是在最后一次大飓风时 在我们的大厅里出生的
This one was born in our lobby during the last big blow
你好汤姆 你好约翰
Hello, Tom. Hello, John
汤姆和约翰是奥西奥拉族的
Tom and John are from the Osceola clan
你好吗
How do you do
我们收到坦普尔先生消息 我们听说应该向警察自首
We get Mr.Temple message. We hear give ourself up to police
他认为这是最好的
He thinks it's the best
坦普尔先生说什么 我们就做什么
What Mr.Temple say, we do
他是印第安人的好朋友
Him good friend to Indian
为什么不去旅馆？爸爸会打电话给棕榈林
Why don't you go to the hotel? Dad'll call Palm Grove
谢谢 诺拉小姐
Thanks, Miss Nora
可怜的家伙们遇到了麻烦还被捕了
Poor fellas got into some trouble and were arrested
我知道 坦普尔先生告诉我他们的事
I know. Mr.Temple told me about them
所有印第安人真的信任爸爸坦普尔
They really trust Dad Temple. All the Indians
就他们而言 他就是美利坚合众国
As far as they're concerned, he's the United States of America
你在这里很开心 不是吗
You're very happy here, aren't you
- 非常 - 你从不孤单
- Very. - You're never lonely
乔治告诉你了吗？我是在舞会上认识他的
Did George tell you? I met him at a USO dance
他很孤独 他需要陪伴
He was lonesome. He wanted company
我在一家国防工厂工作
I was working at a defense plant
我认识很多人 但我也很孤独
I knew lots of people, but I was lonesome too
在乔治之前 我的生活没有多大意义
Before George, my life hadn't made much sense
我从来没有可以称得上家的地方 而且我不喜欢我拥有的东西
I never had much of a home, and I didn't like what I had
乔治给了我根
George gave me roots
他出国时 我来到这和他父亲住在一起 然后扎下了根
When he went overseas, I came here to stay with his father and the roots took hold
现在我就像那些红树林中的一员
Now I'm like one of those mangroves
我们的警察总是抓到他们的印第安人
Our police always get their Indian
在我拿油灯的时候关上窗户
Close the shutters while I get the oil lamps
嘿 伙计 准备好应对飓风了吗
Hey, pal. Getting ready for the hurricane
- 现在和我一起喝点小酒？- 不 谢谢
- Join me for that little drink now? - No, thanks
- 你不喝酒？- 现在不喝
- Not a drinking man? - Not right now
嘿 克里
Hey, Curly
飓风时会发生什么
What all happens in a hurricane
风吹得很厉害 大海用后腿站起来 径直穿过陆地
The wind blows so hard the ocean gets up on its hind legs and walks right across the land
然后唱了一首歌
And singing a song:
雨 雨快走吧 小拉尔菲想玩耍
Rain, rain go away Little Ralphie wants to play
那不是本・韦德的车吗
Isn't that Ben Wade's car
诺拉！你见过他吗
Nora! Have you seen him
不 爸爸 我没有
No, Dad. I haven't
他们正在四处窥探寻找这两个男孩 他们就在这里
They're snooping around looking for these two boys, and here they are
最好出去 坐在他的车里等他
Better go out there and sit in his car and wait for him
更好的是 去找他
Better yet, go and find him
有什么好笑的 图茨
What's so funny, Toots
一个监狱单元中有两个犯人
There are two cons in a cell
一个试图卖给另一个钢笔
One tries to sell the other a fountain pen
他说 这支笔终身保修
And he says, This pen is guaranteed for life
你不明白吗
Don't you get it
一个犯人
A con
终身保修
Guaranteed for life
我们明白了 好吧
We get it, all right
弗兰克 你见过韦德或索耶吗
Have you seen Wade or Sawyer anywhere around, Frank
不 我没有
No, I haven't
- 他的车在雨中停在外面 - 是的 我知道
- His car's out there in the rain. - Yes, I know
这就奇怪了
It's funny
大家喝一杯怎么样？ 坦普尔小姐
How about a drink, everybody? What'll it be, Miss Temple
没什么 谢谢
Nothing, thanks
爸爸 你呢
How about you, Pop
他不应该喝任何东西
He's not supposed to drink anything
就交给你了 伙计
That leaves it up to you, pal
我不了
Another time
怎么了 你不喜欢我吗
What's about it, Don't you like me
我开始怀疑我得了天花什么的
I'm beginning to think I got smallpox or something
还在为那个臭笑话大笑吗
Still laughing at that stinking joke
这是另一个
Here's another one
电梯冲破屋顶
Elevator's busting through a roof
电梯服务员对几个乘客说
The elevator boy says to a couple passengers
我告诉过你没有11层
I told you there was no 11th floor
为我们解释一下 图茨
Explain it for us, Toots
你真聪明
Wise guy
他们的想法是什么
What's the idea of them
他们停掉了电 我们还有油灯
They shut the electricity off, we still have light
我听说飓风会吹翻屋顶 把人们卷起来
I hear a hurricane blows off roofs and puts the snatch on people
它们一起在天空中飞来飞去 是那样的吗
And they all fly around in the sky together. Is that right
当然了
Absolutely
本的车里正在淋雨 最好帮他关上窗户 诺拉
It's raining in on Ben's car. Better close his windows, Nora
拉尔夫 去把那辆车的窗户关上
Ralph, go put up the windows in that car
然后卷入飓风？我不干 兄弟
And get caught out in that hurricane? Not me, brother
我接
I'll take it
你别接那电话
Don't you answer it
不 坦普尔先生现在不在
No, Mr.Temple's not here now
不 她也不在这里
No, she's not here either
我
Me
我是酒店的客人
I'm a guest at the hotel
不 我们还没有见过他
No, we haven't seen him
把电话给我
Give me that phone
是的 如果索耶出现 我会让他马上给你回电话
Yes. If Sawyer shows up, I'll have him call you right back
放松点 士兵
Easy does it, soldier
电话响了 女孩正准备接电话 我阻止了她
The phone rang, and the girl started for it and I stopped her
士兵想动手 所以我们亮了家伙
The soldier wants to get rough, so we show him our rods
我很高兴那老头儿坐轮椅上 否则他会惹很多麻烦
I'm glad the old man's in a wheelchair. He'd be lots of trouble
- 谁打来的电话？- 警察
- Who was on the phone? - The law
那他应该马上到了
That means he won't be long
然后呢
Then what
我们再看
We'll see
你觉得这场雨会让这里变凉快 但竟然没有
You'd think this rain would cool things off, but it don't
- 会有飓风吗？- 他们这么说的
- Gonna have a hurricane? - So they say
我不怕那把枪
I'm not afraid of that gun
来吧！开枪
Go ahead! Shoot
你没胆量开枪
You haven't got the nerve
布朗
Brown
嘿 你！布朗
Hey, you! Brown
你们是小偷吗？你想要钱？这是抢劫吗
Are you thieves? You want money? this a robbery
没错 我们会偷走你所有的毛巾
That's right. We'll steal all your towels
你认为手中的枪让你看起来像个大人
That big gun in your hand makes you look grown-up, you think
我敢打赌你会花几个小时在拿着枪在镜子前摆姿势
I'll bet you spend hours posing in front of a mirror holding it
努力让自己看起来很成熟
Trying to look tough
- 闭嘴 - 你这个败类
- Shut up. - You scum
- 告诉他不要再辱骂我了 - 闭嘴 图茨
- Tell him to stop calling me names. - Shut up, Toots
现在听着
Now listen
我不想惹麻烦 怎么样? 让我们理性一点
I don't want any trouble with you, with anybody. How about it, gonna act sensible
为什么他们用枪指着我们
Why are they pointing guns
不要提问
Forget the questions
你不知道的事情不会伤害你
What you don't know won't hurt you
我们将在几个小时内离开这里
We'll be out of here in a couple of hours
试着忍受我们那么久
Try to put up with us that long
我们今晚吃什么
What'll we eat tonight
鲳鱼 也许
Pompano, maybe
我能理解我们是你的囚犯吗
Am I to understand we're your prisoners
嗯 这么说吧 老爹
Well, put it this way, Pop
你会做一段时间我的客人
you're gonna be my guests for a little while
过去在芝加哥 我们会为一份鲳鱼支付10美元
Back in Chi, in the old days, we used to pay $10 for an order of pompano
他们过去常常空运鲳鱼
They used to fly it in. The way they served it
然后放在一个棕色纸袋中售卖
done up in a brown paper bag
有香槟吗
Got any champagne
没有香槟
No champagne
嗯 这太糟糕了
Well, that's too bad
香槟和鲳鱼
Champagne and pompano
他们真的很搭
They really go together
这个醒了
This one's coming around
还觉得是个硬汉吗
Still feel tough
索耶
Sawyer
你逃不掉的 罗科
You won't get away with it, Rocco
你们为什么要伤害那孩子
Why'd you hurt that boy
他是个警察 这就是原因
He's a cop, that's why
那么 你们是谁
Well, who are you
你们为什么在这里
Why are you here
- 回答我！- 别喊了 老头子
- Answer me! - Stop hollering, old man
当然是约翰尼·罗科
Johnny Rocco, of course
热水
Hot water
去取一些
Get some
是的 没错
Yeah, that's right
约翰尼·罗科
Johnny Rocco
- 我知道那个名字 - 当然 谁不知道
- I know that name. - Sure, who doesn't
黑手党的约翰尼·罗科 坦普尔先生
Johnny Rocco the gangster, Mr.Temple
独一无二的罗科
The one and only Rocco
罗科 罗科
Rocco Rocco
那是什么 老爹？我有点聋了
What's that, Pop? I'm kind of deaf
罗科
Rocco
他说 罗科
He said Rocco
但是他们把你赶出了这个国家
But they threw you out of the country
是的 没错
Yeah, that's right
在美国生活了30年 他们称我为不被需要的外国人
After living in the U.S.A. for more than 30 years they called me an undesirable alien
我 约翰尼·罗科
Me, Johnny Rocco
就像我是一个肮脏的康米什么的
Like I was a dirty Red or something
那你怎么会在这里
Then how could you be here
嗯 也许我不是 老爹
Well, maybe I'm not, Pop
这不是真的 你是在做梦
This ain't real. You're having a dream
醒来吧 老爹 你在打鼾
Wake up pop you're snoring
你是对的
You're right
你不应该被驱逐出境
You shouldn't have been deported
你早该被消灭了
You should've been exterminated
罗科 我为坦普尔先生道歉 他不知道自己在说什么
Rocco I apologize for Mr.Temple. He doesn't know what he's talking about
罗科不仅仅是一位国王 他是一位皇帝
Rocco was more than a king. He was an emperor
他统治啤酒、老虎机、数字球拍和其他被禁止的产业
His rule extended over beer, slot machines, the numbers racket and other forbidden enterprises
他是那些行当的大师
He was a master of the fix
无法被腐化的人 他会恐吓或谋杀
Whom he couldn't corrupt, he terrified or murdered
你这个肮脏的东西！你这个城市的污物
You filth! You city filth
坦普尔先生 你真是太过时了
Mr.Temple, you're hopelessly old-fashioned
当时美国认为没有约翰尼·罗科斯也能过得去
Your ideas date back years to the time when America thought it could get along without the Johnny Roccos
欢迎回来 罗科先生 一切都是误会
Welcome back, Mr.Rocco. It was all a mistake
美国对它对你们的所作所为感到抱歉
America's sorry for what it did to you
真的吗 老大 你有那么伟大吗
On the level, boss, were you that big
真的吗 你有那么笨吗
On the level, are you that dumb
是的 这就是我
Yeah, that's me
当然 我就是这么伟大
Sure, I was all of those things
甚至更加伟大
And more
当罗科讲话时 所有人都闭嘴倾听
When Rocco talked, everybody shut up and listened
罗科说去做 有人就去做
What Rocco said, went
没有人像罗科一样伟大
Nobody was as big as Rocco
它会再次伟大 只会更伟大
It'll be like that again, only more so
有一天我会再次伟大 你们会看到我的壮举
I'll be back up there one day. Then you'll really see something
如果有一天 你们这些人可以毫无恐惧的走在街上...
If the time ever comes when your kind can walk a city street in daylight with nothing to fear from the people...
现在就是那天 坦普尔先生 就是现在
The time has come, Mr.Temple. It's here
你了解我的一切
You know all about me
那么 聪明的家伙 你又怎样
Now, what's with you, wise guy
好呀 说吧
Well, give
你参加了战争 不是吗
In the war, weren't you
- 获得任何勋章？- 有一些
- Get any medals? - A couple
- 很勇敢？- 不是特别地
- Brave? - Not very
- 你为什么要出头？- 没什么理由
- Why'd you stick your neck out? - No good reason
你在说什么？弗兰克
What are you saying? Frank
我相信一些话
I believed some words
话？什么话
Words? What words
好吧 是这样的
Well, they went like this
人类的努力和牺牲
But we aren't making all this sacrifice of human effort and lives
并没有换回世界大战前的世界
to return to the kind of a world we had after the last world war
我们正在为清除世界上古老的邪恶而战
We're fighting to cleanse the world of ancient evils
古老的弊病 (注：出自1942年罗斯福的美国国情咨文)
Ancient ills
那是什么意思
What's that about
我记得那些话
I remember those words
那就是我们两个人
That makes two of us
我们一劳永逸地摆脱了你们
We rid ourselves of your kind once and for all
你不会回来了
You ain't coming back
谁能阻止我 老人
Who's gonna stop me, old man
如果我不是瘸子...
If I wasn't a cripple...
那你就不会这样乱叫了 对吧 老爹
You wouldn't be talking this way. Right, Pop
污秽！你这个污秽
Filth! You filth
抓住他 好吗
Get him, will you
- 攻击他 老爹！- 站起来
- Sic him, Pop! - Stand your ground
老爹 你快要杀死我了
You're killing me, Pop
加油 老爹！你不会放弃 是吧
Come on, Pop! You're not quitting, are you
我的孩子 乔治 永远不会放弃 我也不会放弃
My boy, George, never quit, and I ain't quitting
就是这精神 老爹！永不言败
That's the spirit, Pop! Never say die
你这个小野猫
You little wildcat
闻到了血腥味 是吧
Smelled blood, huh
胃口大开 是吧
Got your appetite up, huh
嘿 老板
Hey, boss
迈阿密希望你接听电话
Miami wants you on the phone
门廊上的人看起来像印第安人
The people on the porch look like Indians
- 他们想要什么？- 他们想进来
- What do they want? - They want in
- 为什么？- 飓风来了
- What for? - The hurricane
别让他们进来
Keep them out
是的 这是布朗先生
Yeah, this is Mr.Brown
你好 齐吉！你好吗
Hello, Ziggy! How are you
我认出了你的声音
I recognized your voice
当然 我的听力很好
Well, swell hearing it again
过得怎么样
How's every little thing
- 也许是警察 - 让他进来
- Maybe it's the law. - Show him in
这太棒了
That's swell
这边也很好
This end too
你什么时候过来
Look, when are you coming down
什么飓风？是吗
What hurricane? That right
- 我想见老板 - 是船长
- I want to see the boss. - It's the skipper
坦普尔先生 拜托
Mr.Temple, please
你只有两个小时的路程 你可以战胜飓风的
You're only two hours away. You can beat the hurricane out
不行 必须是今晚
No, it's gotta be tonight
是的 几个小时后见
Yeah, see you in a couple of hours
再见
Bye
暴风雨警告 路上的风很大
Storm warning. Big blow on the way
- 那又怎样？-这片珊瑚礁不安全
- So what? - This coral reef not safe
必须立即前往深水区
Got to make for deep water right away
那艘船就停在这里
That boat stays here
太危险了 船会撞到礁石
Too dangerous. Boat break up on reef
我告诉你什么时候开船
I tell you when to move that boat
我是船长
I am skipper
我付了钱给你
Now, look, I paid you
- 你照我说的做 - 麻烦了 先生
- You do what I say. - Please, señor
你想要一半的钱吗？我给
You want half money back? I give
但必须改变方向
But got to move boat
把你的家伙给我
Give me your rod
看到这个了吗
See this
你动那条船 我就炸掉你的脑袋
You move that boat, I'll blow your brains out
我们将在两小时内离开这里
We'll be out of here in two hours
我会准备好
I'll be ready
出去把那辆车绕到后面
Go out and move that car around the back
我回来这里是为了寻找那两个奥西奥拉男孩
I come back here looking for those Osceola boys
我知道他们就在这附近的某个地方
I knew they were somewhere around here
在大厅里 我遇到了这两个人
Down the lobby, I ran up against these two
我觉得他们不对 所以我问了他们几个问题
They didn't look right to me, so I asked them a few questions
从他们回答的方式来看 我知道有些不对劲
By the way they answered, I knew there was something fishy
所以我给本·韦德警官打了个电话 但我眼前就黑了
So I put in a call to Ben Wade, but the lights went out on me
我在那里醒来
I woke up in there
罗科站在我面前
Rocco was standing over me
我一眼就认出了他
I recognized him right away from pictures
我冲出门去 眼前又黑了下来
I made a break for the door, and the lights went out again
我关的灯
I'm the electrician
安吉尔
Angel
刮胡子
Shave
迈阿密说了什么
What did Miami have to say
一切都好
Everything's okay
他们多久会来
How soon will they be down
他们马上就要出发了
They were leaving right away
小警官 感觉如何
How're you feeling, copper
我要说一件事 你肯定能接受
I'll say one thing, you sure can take it
顺便说一句 图茨把把你打昏的 我很惊讶你能醒来
By the way Toots poured it on, I'm surprised you ever woke up
啊 真的好热
Boy, sure is hot
围巾别太紧
Not too close
所以我没法逃掉 是吧
So I won't get away with it, huh
我从蠢警察那里听到了多少次这样的话
How many times I heard that from dumb coppers
我仍要告诉你这样的话
I still say it
你会用你的左眼来盯着我 不是吗
You'd give your left eye to nail me, wouldn't you
你可以看到那头条 不是吗
You can see the headlines, can't you
地方辅警逮捕约翰尼·罗科
Local Deputy Captures Johnny Rocco
你的照片会出现在所有的报纸上
Your picture would be in all the papers
你甚至可以在新闻片上讲述你是如何成功的
You might even get to tell on the newsreel how you pulled it off
好吧 听着 乡巴佬
Well, listen, hick
对于任何大城市的警察来说 我都难以应付
I was too much for any big-city police force to handle
他们尝试过 但他们做不到
They tried, but they couldn't
美国政府指责我
Took the U.S. government to pin a rap on me
是的 但他们坚持不下去
Yeah, and they won't make it stick
你这乡巴佬
You hick
我能让人被选为市长 州长
I'll be back-pulling strings and getting guys elected mayor and governor. .
而在这之前你只能得到10美元加薪
before you ever get a $10 raise
办公室里有多少人的一切都归功于我
How many of those guys in office owe everything to me
我造就了他们
I made them
我造就了他们 就像裁缝做衣服一样
I made them, just like a tailor makes a suit of clothes
我找一个无名小卒 教他说什么 让他的名字出现在新闻中
I take a nobody, teach him what to say, get his name in the papers
我支付他的竞选费用
I pay for his campaign expenses
送出大量杂货和煤炭
Dish out a lot of groceries and coal
让我的手下把选民拉出来
Get my boys to bring the voters out
然后再次统计票数
Then count the votes again
直到票数正确 他被选中
till they added up right, and he was elected
然后发生了什么
Then what happened
他还记得事情变得麻烦的时候吗
Did he remember when the going got tough
当麻烦火热时
When the heat was on
不 他不想
No, he didn't want to
他只想保住自己肮脏的脖子
All he wanted was to save his own dirty neck
够了 给我一条毛巾 好吗
That's enough of that. Give me a towel, will you
全民公敌 他这样称呼我
Public Enemy, he calme
我 像给了他礼物一样 给了他一切公共权力的我
Me, who gave him his public all wrapped up with a fancy bow on it
安吉尔 把我的衣服拿出来
Angel, lay my clothes out
- 什么花色？- 灰色的
- What suit? - The gray one
- 什么颜色的衬衫？- 当然是白色的
- What color shirt? - A white one, of course
小野猫
Some little wildcat
很久以前我就认识像你这样的人
I knew one like you a long time ago
又抓 又踢 又咬
Scratched, kicked, bit
常见的坏猫
Regular hellion
有一次她甚至用刀刺我
She even stuck a knife in me once
爱尔兰女孩
Irish kid
她很小 有点瘦
Little and kind of skinny she was
但却是真正的火辣
but a real fireball
她的名字叫玛吉·穆尼
Her name was Maggie Mooney
但出于专业原因 我不得不把她改名为唐・盖伊
But for professional reasons, I had to change it to Gaye Dawn
那时的她令人惊叹
She was a knockout in those days
为什么你
Why, you
来吧 老板 打她 释放你的愤怒
Go ahead, boss, smack her. Get it out of your system
看看他 伟大的约翰尼·罗科
Look at him. The great Johnny Rocco
脸上挂着诺拉的唾沫
With Nora's spittle hanging from his face
闭嘴 老家伙
Shut up, old man
过来 我想吐你一口
Come over here. I'd like to spit on you
给我
Give me
没有什么能阻止我把你们全部杀死
Nothing to stop me from wiping you all out
那有什么用呢？她那种人一毛钱一打
What good'll that do? Her kind's a dime a dozen
给她一巴掌就算了吧
Smack her and let it go at that
这适合你 不适合他
That'd be right for you, not for him
我没有征求你的意见
I didn't ask for your advice
罗科不会征求意见 否则他就不是罗科
The Roccos don't, or they wouldn't be Roccos
不 打她是不够的 他必须杀了她
No, smacking her isn't enough. He'd have to kill her
然后他必须杀死那些目击它的人
Then he'd have to kill those who witnessed it
不仅是坦普尔先生和我 还有所有目击者
Not just Mr.Temple and me, but all the witnesses
要么杀掉所有人 要么都不杀
It's kill us all or nothing
罗科需要你、克里还有安吉尔
He needs you and Curly and Angel
所以谁都不用死
So it'll be nothing
聪明人
Wise guy
打开这扇门
Unlock this door
打开这扇门！我想出去
Unlock this door! I want out
让她出来
Let her out
我向你脱帽致敬 士兵
I take off my hat to you, soldier
你说得好 否则他会开枪的
It's good you said what you said, or he'd have started shooting
太险了 比安吉尔给罗科刮胡子还要危险
Close shave for you folks. Closer than the one he got from Angel
大家在哪里？楼下
Where is everybody? Downstairs
大家好
Hello, everybody
嗨 伙计
Hi, fella
约翰尼在哪里
Where's Johnny
他在里面穿衣服
He's in there getting dressed
我需要喝一杯
I need a drink
大家在楼上做什么
What's everybody doing upstairs
亲爱的
Honey
你在哭吗
Have you been crying
为什么？有人对你不好吗
Why? Has somebody been mean to you
你惹她哭了吗？ 如果是 你应该感到羞耻
Did you make her cry? if you did, you ought to be ashamed
- 喝点酒怎么样？- 不 谢谢
- How about a little drink? - No, thanks
哦 来吧 它会赶走忧愁的
Oh, come on. It'll chase the blues away
- 我要来一杯 - 老板说...
- I'll have one. - The boss said--
我不在乎老板说什么 我需要喝一杯
I don't care what the boss said. I need a drink
- 晚上好 坦普尔先生 - 小姐
- Good evening, Mr.Temple. - Miss
你有烟吗
You got a cigarette
你的马赢了吗
Did your horse win
我的马
My horse
不 恐怕他没钱了
No, I'm afraid he ran out of the money
对不起
I'm sorry
我想我会去我的房间
I think I'll go to my room
我感到头晕
I feel faint
我需要的是一杯酒
What I need is a drink
这就是我需要的
That's what I need
说吧 怎么样
Say, how about it
我要说多少次
How many times do I have to tell you
老板说不要再喝酒了
The boss say no more drink
哦 他说了 是吗
Oh, he did, did he
嗯 这是一个自由的国家
Well, this is a free country
如果我想喝一杯 我可以喝一杯
If I want a drink, I can have one
我可以自己买 拿着
I can buy my own. There
抱歉
Sorry
-老板说---老板！老板！他可以去地...
- The boss say-- - The boss! The boss! He can go to...
你好 亲爱的
Hello, darling
为什么晚上会比白天还热
How come it's hotter at night than in the day
下雨的时候比不下雨的时候还热
And when it's raining than when it ain't
哈 聪明人
Huh, wise guy
我不知道
I don't know
你不知道
You don't know
我以为你知道所有的答案
I thought you knew all the answers
我以为你是从远古来的智者
I thought you was a wise guy from way back
亲爱的 你伤到了自己
Darling, you've hurt yourself
你的脸！到底怎...
Your face! How in the world--
- 有什么好笑的？-没有
- What's funny? - Nothing
你为什么笑
Why'd you laugh
我不知道
I don't know
傻子
Dumbbell
哪个更糟 克里
What's worse, Curly
傻子还是聪明人
A dumbbell or a wise guy
我想是聪明人
A wise guy, I guess
有百万美元吗
Got a million dollars
- 你有多少钱？- 没多少
- How much? - Nothing
但你是个聪明人
But you're a wise guy
你看 我只接受了不切实际的教育
You see, I was educated only in impractical things
对你来说 情况恰恰相反
With you, it's the opposite
我害怕 我讨厌打雷
I'm afraid. I hate thunder
这就是飓风 是吗
Is this it? it
- 这只是开始 - 我害怕
- It's the beginning. - I'm afraid
汽车可以在飓风期间通过吗
Can cars get through during a hurricane
也许吧 也许不会
Maybe. Maybe not
我觉得我需要
I think I'll have
一杯苏格兰威士忌兑水
a scotch and water, please
- 拜托 亲爱的！-不
- Please, darling! - No
你说的是真的
What you were saying is true
只是你不相信 我看透了你
Only you don't believe it. I see through you
你认为 我比罗科强
You think, "I'm better than Rocco
他是个肮脏的人！就像那老头子说的 对吧
He's filth! " Like the old man said. Right
对
Right
你在想 他有枪但我没有
"He has a gun," you think, "I haven't. "
你觉得是枪的原因
You figure it's the gun
好吧 听着 士兵
Well, listen, soldier
成千上万的人有枪 但只有一个约翰尼·罗科
thousands of guys got guns, but there's only one Johnny Rocco
那又怎样
How do you account for it
他知道自己想要什么
He knows what he wants
- 是吗 罗科？- 当然
- Don't you, Rocco? - Sure
又怎么了
What's that
告诉他 罗科
Tell him, Rocco
好吧 我想要...
Well, I want...
他想要更多 不是吗 罗科
He wants more. Don't you, Rocco
就是这样！更多
That's it! More
没错 我想要更多
That's right, I want more
你会满足吗
Will you ever get enough
你愿意满足吗 罗科
Will you, Rocco
嗯 我从来不满足
Well, I never have
不 我想我不会
No, I guess I won't
你知道你想要什么吗
Do you know what you want
是的 我曾经有过希望 但我放弃了
Yes, and I had hopes once, but I gave them up
希望什么
Hopes for what
一个没有约翰尼·罗科容身之地的世界
A world in which there's no place for Johnny Rocco
好的 士兵
Okay, soldier
机会来了
Here's your chance
给我
Give me
好的 士兵 你可以让你的希望成真
Okay, soldier, you can make your hopes come true
但你必须为此而死
But you gotta die for it
看到我瞄准哪了吗？你的肚子
See where I'm aiming? At your belly
来吧 开枪
Go ahead, shoot
- 走开 小姐 - 走开 诺拉
- Get away, sister. - Get away, Nora
开枪
Shoot
好吧 你现在有枪了 你会开枪还是不会
All right, you got a gun now. You gonna use it or not
杀了他 少校
Kill him, major
是的 杀了他 少校
Yeah, kill him, major
向他们展示你是不怕死的
Show them how you're not afraid to die
开枪
Shoot
看来你并不是那么希望啊
Looks like you don't want it enough
当事情变得有趣时 他会笑
He laughs when something's funny for a change
多一个罗科 少一个罗科 不值得为之送命
One Rocco more or less isn't worth dying for
把枪给我
Give me that gun
不 恐怕你会开枪
No, I'm afraid you'd use it
有一个老头儿 没一个老头儿 不值得为之送命
One old man more or less isn't worth dying for
怎么了 小姐
What's the matter, sister
你看起来就像失去了亲人
You look like you lost somebody near and dear
一个活生生的战争英雄
A live war hero
现在我知道你是怎么成为战争英雄的了
Now I know how you did it
克里 盖伊 随便谁
Curly, Gaye, anybody
有人相当英雄吗
Want a hero
这里出售英雄 非常便宜
Here's one for sale, cheap
好的 罗科
All right, Rocco
好吧
All right
现在让你和我来玩这个游戏吧
Let's you and me play that game now
你可以阻止我走出那扇门
You can stop me from going out that door
但你必须先死
But you gotta die first
如果他向我开枪 你明白我会开枪
If he shoots me, you still get it
别挡我的路
Get out of my way
离开那扇门
Get away from that door
枪没有上膛
The gun wasn't loaded
他没有机会
He didn't have a chance
杀人犯
Murderer
不得不这样做 老人
Had to do it, old man
否则他会走出那扇门然后离开
Or he would've been out that door and gone
他现在走了
He's gone now
没错 小姐 枪没有上膛
That's right, sister. The gun wasn't loaded
但我们的英雄并不知道
But our hero didn't know it
你知道枪是空的 不是吗 孩子
You knew the gun was empty, didn't you, son
你可以通过重量来判断
You could tell by the weight
不 先生 我不知道
No, sir. I didn't know
他只是没那胆子
He just didn't have the nerve
让我们面对现实吧
Let's face it
伙计 你很聪明
You were smart, fella
发生在他身上的事也会发生在你身上
What happened to him would've happened to you
做一个活着的懦夫比做一个死去的英雄要好
It's better to be a live coward than a dead hero
抱歉
Excuse me
你并不害怕 我们都知道
You weren't afraid. We all know that
哦 不 我很害怕
Oh, yes, I was afraid
但这不是我不开枪的原因
But that's not why I didn't shoot
我为什么要在乎约翰尼·罗科的生死
What do I care whether Johnny Rocco lives or dies
我只关心我自己！我 我的生死
I only care about me! Me and mine
罗科想回到美国 让他去吧！让他当总统
Rocco wants to come back to America, let him! Let him be President
除了我自己 我不为任何人而战
I fight nobody's battles but my own
我不明白你的意思 弗兰克
I can't see it your way, Frank
索耶也不明白
Sawyer didn't either
他是个傻瓜
He was a fool
我为了让世界摆脱约翰尼·罗科而死？
Me, die to rid the world of a Johnny Rocco?
不了 谢谢
No, thanks
如果我相信你的信仰...
If I believed your way...
...我也想死
...I'd want to be dead too
的确
It's true
你是个胆小鬼
You are a coward
你现在说的只是为了面子
What you're saying now is only to save your corward's face
别说了 诺拉
Now, Nora
也许弗兰克是对的
maybe Frank's right
也许他是对的
Maybe he's right
有什么想法 齐吉？你为什么还不来
What's the idea, Ziggy? Why ain't you started yet
那又怎样
So what
怎么了 你们？我没有冒险吗
What's the matter, you guys? Didn't I take chances
我从古巴逃跑 冒着我的性命 我的船和货物的风险
I make the run from Cuba, risk my neck, my boat and the shipment
而你却不愿从雨中出来
and you won't come out in the rain
听我说 要么你今晚出现 要么交易取消
Listen to me. Either you show tonight or the deal is off
我知道有十几个人愿意为这批货不惜一切代价
I know a dozen guys who'd break their necks to get this shipment
听着 我的手表说
Look, my watch says. .
现在是8点
8:00
我给你两个小时 10点你还没到 交易就取消
I give you two hours. You ain't here by 10, the deal is off
喂
Hello
去楼下 所有人
Downstairs, everybody
我不是说过不可以喝酒吗
Didn't I say no drinking
拜托 亲爱的 只喝一杯
Please, honey. Just one
把货拿下来
Bring down the shipment
在那里
In there
坦普尔先生！坦普尔先生
Mr.Temple! Mr.Temple
等等
Wait
有人在那吗
Is that someone calling
印第安人站在门口 我把他们送走了
Indians were at the door. I sent them away
你做得不对
You'd no right
听听
Listen to it
楼上的窗户必须关上 要么屋顶可能会被吹翻
The upstairs shutters gotta be closed, or the roof might come off
关上窗户
Go close them
我无法忍受一位女酒鬼
One thing I can't stand is a dame that's drunk
她们让我反胃
What I mean, they turn my stomach
对她们自己或其他任何人都没有好处
No good to themselves or anybody else
她在发抖了 看
She got the shakes, see
所以她喝了一杯来不再发抖 然后她又喝一杯
So she has a drink to get rid of them. Then she has another
最后 她就成酒鬼了
First thing you know, she's stinko again
你给了我第一杯酒
You gave me my first drink
哦 所以现在都是我的错了
Oh, so it's all my fault now
每个人都会喝第一杯酒 但不是所有人都是酒鬼
Everybody has their first drink, but everybody ain't a lush
如果我知道你会这样 我就不会来这里了
If I'd known you'd act this way, I wouldn't have come here
如果我知道你是个酒鬼 就不会请你来了
If I'd known what you're like, you wouldn't have been asked
自从我见到她已经8年了
Eight years since I seen her
你不会觉得这是同一位女士
You wouldn't know it's the same dame
你肯定一点都没有改变
You certainly haven't changed one bit
什么意思
Meaning what
没什么意思
Nothing
哎呀 你太刻薄了
Gee, you're as mean as can be
刻薄就刻薄 这让我想起了什么
Mean as can be. Now what does that remind me of
你不记得了吗
Don't you remember
那是在一首歌里 她曾经唱过
That was in a song. She used to sing it
是的 没错
Yeah, that's right
我给了她第一次机会 让她成为一名歌手
I gave her her first chance, made her a singer
对了 为什么你不是一个歌星而不是一个酒鬼
Mention that. Why ain't you a singing star instead of a lush
约翰尼 我说你刻薄不代表什么
Johnny, I didn't mean anything
是的 她本可以拥有未来
Yeah, she could've had a future
她拥有一切
She had everything
嗓音
Voice
样貌
Looks
教养
Plenty of class
我当时很生气
I was the rage
哎呀 亲爱的
Gee, honey
现在 盖伊 听着
Now, look, Gaye. .
你为什么不给我们唱唱你的老歌呢
why don't you give us your old song
你是说 现在
You mean, right now
- 我不能 - 你当然可以
- I can't. - Sure you can
请不要逼我
Please don't make me
我不会强迫你做任何事情
I won't make you do anything
我有一个建议给你
I got a proposition for you
唱首歌 你可以喝一杯
Sing a song, you can have a drink
我可以先喝一杯吗
Can I have the drink first
不！先唱歌
No! The song
然后是酒
Then the drink
没有任何伴奏
Without any accompaniment
你到底想不想喝一杯
Now, look, do you want a drink or don't you
好吧
All right
开始吧
Well
我的礼服很华丽
My gowns were gorgeous
始终低领
Always low-cut
非常性感
Very décolleté
我几乎没有化妆
I wore hardly any makeup
只是一些口红 仅此而已
Just some lipstick, that's all
没有灯光 只有一个聚光灯
No lights, just a baby spot
我不会有任何入场仪式 他们会在黑暗中演奏前奏
I wouldn't have any entrance. They'd play the intro in the dark
然后舞台一处升起
and a spot would come on
我会在那里
and there I'd be
来吧！唱歌
Go ahead! Sing
低吟
Moaning low
我亲爱的 我爱他
My sweet man, I love him so
虽然他很刻薄
Though he's mean as can be
他是那种人
He's the kind of man
需要那种女人
Needs the kind of woman
像我这样的
Like me
欲死
Gonna die
如果甜蜜的男人从我身边经过
If sweet man should pass me by
如果我死了 他会在哪里
If I die, where will he be
他是那种人
He's the kind of man
需要那种女人
Needs the kind of woman
像我这样的
Like me
不知道什么原因
Don 't know any reason
为什么他对我这么差
Why he treats me so poorly
我做了什么
What have I gone and done
有了他的担忧 让我的麻烦加倍
Makes my trouble double with his worries
什么时候他会确定
When surely
我不值得拥有
I ain 't deserving of none
低吟
Moaning low
我亲爱的人要走了
My sweet man is gonna go
当他离开时 哦 上帝
When he goes, oh, Lordy
他是那种人
He's the kind of man
需要那种女人
Needs the kind of woman
像我这样的
Like me
现在给我那杯酒
Give me that drink now
- 但你答应了！- 所以呢
- But you promised! - So what
- 你说过 - 但你已经腐烂
- You said that-- - But you were rotten
谢谢 伙计
Thanks, fella
不客气
You're welcome
打牌吗
Play a little gin
- 赌多少钱？- 你说个数
- For how much? - Name it
一分一毛钱
Nickel a point
嘿 老头儿
Hey, old man
它能变得多糟糕
How bad can it get
我在问你问题！你听到了吗
I asked you a question! Did you hear me
我们经历过的最严重的暴风雨发生在35年
Worst storm we ever had was back in '35
风掀起一个大浪打到基・马特库姆贝
Wind whipped up a big wave and sent it busting right over Matecumbe Key
八百人被卷入大海
Eight hundred people were washed out to sea
那离这里有多远
How far away was that from here
几英里
A few miles
听听
Listen to it
抱歉我在楼上说的话
Sorry about the things I said upstairs
它们不是真的 你能原谅我么 弗兰克
They aren't true. Will you forgive me? Frank
当然
Of course
他可能杀了你 但就算如此 你不得不帮助她
He might've killed you, but that makes no difference, you had to help her
你的脑袋认为是这样 但你的整个生命却是另一个样子
Your head said one way, but your whole life said another
其他事情 也许是真的 也许这是一个腐烂的世界
The other things, maybe they're true. Maybe it is a rotten world
但如果有人愿意为其战斗 信仰就不会完结
But a cause isn't lost if someone's willing to fight
我不是那种人
I'm not that someone
你是
But you are
你可能不想成为 但你情不自禁
You may not want to be, but you can't help yourself
你的一生都在与你的思想作对
Your whole life's against you
你对我的生活了解多少
What do you know about my life
很多
A whole lot
从你的外表和说话方式 和乔治写给我的东西
From the way you look and talk, and from things George wrote me
他最后一封信的大部分内容都是关于你和他的电话
Most of his last letter was all about you and him on the phone
只不过他的故事与你的相反 你才是那个在山上的人
Only he had it the other way. You were the one on the hill
你又怎么了
What's the matter with you
没什么
Nothing
为什么大家都这么安静
Why's everybody so quiet
说话啊 你为什么不说话
Talk, why don't you
克里 说点什么
Curly, say something
- 你想让我说什么？- 任何事情 随便说点
- What do you want me to say? - Anything, just so it's talk
- 来吧！- 我在努力思考
- Go ahead! - I'm trying to think
我跟你打赌两三年 我们会恢复禁酒令
I bet you two or three years, we get Prohibition back
这次我们让禁酒令持续下去
This time we make it stick
我跟你打赌两三年 禁酒令又回来了
I bet you two or three years, Prohibition comes back
绝对 是的
Absolutely, yeah
问题是 以前有太多人想成为头号人物
The trouble was, before, too many guys wanted to be top dog
这就是问题所在
That was the trouble
一群暴徒开始屠杀另一群暴徒
One mob gets to massacring another
报纸大肆宣传 大肆宣传 看到了吗
The papers play it up big. Big, see
- 那么会发生什么？- 所以呢
- So what happens? - So what
报纸和公众大肆宣传
The papers play it up big, and the public
然后大家明白了禁酒令不好
gets the idea that Prohibition's no good
如果他们能摆脱它
That if they can get rid of it
- 摆脱禁酒令 我的意思是 - 我不相信
- Prohibition, I mean... - I don't believe it
八百人被冲入大海 你是个骗子
Eight hundred guys washed out to sea. You're a liar
如果真发生了那种事 这里就不会再有人住了
Nobody would live here after that happened
- 他们还会在这住吗？- 我记得在报纸上读到过这事
- Would they? - I remember reading it in the papers
从迈阿密派出救援列车
A relief train was dispatched from Miami
气压计降至最低
The barometer was down to about 26 inches
那列火车驶入霍姆斯特德时
when that train pulled into Homestead
工程师将一串空车厢推入危险区域
Engineer backed his string of empty coaches into the danger zone
然后飓风来了
and the hurricane hit
把那些火车直接撞出轨
Knocked those coaches right off the track
风速达到了每小时两百英里
Two hundred miles an hour, that wind blew
12英尺高的潮汐穿过佛罗里达群岛
A tidal wave 1 2 feet high went right across the Key
整个城镇都被移平
Whole towns were wiped out
数英里的轨道被掀起
Miles and miles of track were ripped up
然后被冲走 什么都没有留下
and washed away. Nothing was left
暴风雨过后 找到了500多具尸体
More than 500 bodies were recovered after the storm
之后的几个月
And for months afterwards
在红树林沼泽中发现了尸体
corpses were found in the mangrove swamps
你不喜欢它 是吗？暴风雨
You don't like it, do you? The storm
拿出你的枪 为什么不呢
Show it your gun, why don't you
如果它不停下来 就开枪打它
If it doesn't stop, shoot it
所以公众投票反对禁酒令
So the public votes out Prohibition
这就是暴徒的终结
And that's the end of the mobs
下次会有所不同
Next time, it'll be different
我们吸取了教训 好吧
We learned our lesson, all right
下一次 暴徒会团结在一起
Next time, the mobs'll get together
掀起大浪
Make the big wave
让它向我们冲来
Send it crashing down on us
如果需要 摧毁我们所有人 但要惩罚他
Destroy us all, if need be. But punish him
闭嘴 老头儿！我警告你！闭嘴
Shut up, old man! I'm warning you! Shut up
听从我 听从我
Hear me. Hear me
我会杀了你
I'll kill you
掀起大浪
Make a big wave
让它向我们冲来 把我们都带走
Send it against us. Take us all
但要摧毁他
But destroy him
坦普尔先生
Mr.Temple
暴风雨过去了
The storm's passing
一两个破旧的窗户 海滩上有一些垃圾
A torn shutter or two, some trash on the beach
几个小时后 几乎没有什么可以提醒你发生过什么
In a few hours, there'll be little to remind you of what happened
我们还会再见到你吗 弗兰克
Will we ever see you again Frank
暴风雨
The storm
它正在离去
It's passing
- 我们还会见吗？- 希望如此
- Will we? - I hope so
你为什么不和我们一起呆在这里
Why don't you stay here with us
我们欢迎你
You're most welcome
继续 告诉他 诺拉
Go on, tell him Nora
如果他决定留在这里 我们会非常高兴
If he decides to stay here with us, we'd be most happy
继续 告诉弗兰克
Go on, tell Frank
- 你有什么亲人吗？ - 没有
- Have you any folks? - No
如果你将我们视为你的家人 我会很自豪
I'd be proud to have you regard us as your family
也许这不是弗兰克想要的
Maybe that isn't what Frank wants
我并不是要强迫你 孩子
I don't mean to set onto you, son
再想想 不用马上给出你的答案
Think it over. Don't give your answer right away
嘿 老板！嘿 老板
Hey, boss! Hey, boss
- 怎么了？- 船不见了
- What's the matter? - The boat's gone
船长把船开走了
He did it
我告诉他我会杀了他 他还是把船开走了
I told him I'd kill him. He did it just the same
- 也许他会回来 暴风雨结束了 - 不会的
- Maybe he'll come back. The storm's over. - No
为什么不会
Why not
他相信我会杀了他
He believed I'd kill him
我们要做什么
What'll we do
- 我们不能留在这里！- 真的
- We can't stay here! - Can we
嘿 老大
Hey, boss
你的错 小姐
Your mistake, sister
- 我们没有遇到任何麻烦 - 有办法吗
- We're not in any trouble. - Got something
那里还有另一艘船 不大 但可以带我们去古巴
There's another boat out there. It ain't much, but it'll get us to Cuba
谁来驾驶它
Who's going to run it
他
Him
坦普尔先生！你不是好人
Mr.Temple! You not good man
你不让任何人进来！这不好
You not let nobody in! That's no good
汤姆·奥西奥拉
Tom Osceola
- 汤姆！汤姆... - 闭嘴
- Tom! Tom... - Shut up
你让妇女和婴儿陷入暴风雨？这不好
You leave women and baby out in storm? That no good
你不再是朋友了 我们不再按你说做了
You no more friend. We no do like you say anymore
不再去找本・韦德了！你不是印第安人的好朋友
No go Ben Wade! You no good friend to Indian
你告诉过我 你把他们赶走了
You told me you sent them away
你骗了我 整个暴风雨期间 他们都在我门外
You lied to me. They were outside my door during the whole storm
- 那又怎样？- 他们可能会死在那里
- So what? - They might've died out there
谁在乎呢
And who cares
你这个肮脏的东西
You filth
他说的 你可以开船 这是真的
What he said, you can run a boat. That's a fact
他的初恋情人是一艘船
His first sweetheart was a boat
你带我们去古巴
You're taking us to Cuba
- 我为什么要这样做？- 你知道如果你不这样做会发生什么
- Why should l? - You know what'll happen if you don't
我不会带你去的
I won't take you
你宁愿死也不愿带我们
You'd rather die than take us
我没那么说
I didn't say that
你杀不了我 我是你逃脱这里的唯一机会
You won't kill me. I'm your only chance of getting away from here
还有其他方法可以让你就范 对吧 图茨
There's other ways of getting at you. Right, Toots
对
Right
- 也许我不会就范 - 你会的
- Maybe I'm up to them. - You wouldn't be
和图茨相处几分钟后 你会开始问这样的问题
After a few minutes of Toots, you'll begin to ask questions like:
如果我之后变成跛子怎么办
What if I come out of this a cripple
我在乎他们逃跑吗
And "Do I care whether they make their getaway or don't?"
你所有的答案都是正确的
All your answers would be right ones
- 我不确定 - 我确定
- I'm not so sure. - I am
当然 如果你急于知道
Of course, if you're anxious to find out
你能忍受何种程度 我们会满足你的要求
just how good you are at taking it, we'll accommodate you
但我警告你
But I warn you
图茨没有太多练习
Toots hasn't had much practice
有点生疏 可能会失手
Kind of rusty. Might slip
那太糟糕了
And that would be too bad
因为你在楼上说的很有道理
Because you made real sense upstairs when you said. .
多一个罗科 少一个罗科 不值得为之送命
one Rocco more or less ain't worth dying for
齐吉
Ziggy
警察
The law
任何人只要说错一个字 他就会和索耶一样
One wrong word out of anybody and he gets it the same as Sawyer did
明白我的意思吗 老头儿
Understand me, old man
现在 你 小姐 让他进来
Now, you, sister, let him in
晚上好
Good evening
我在找索耶 他在这里吗
I'm looking for Sawyer. Is he here
- 他来过这里吗？- 没有
- Has he been here? - No
这很有趣 大约7:00 他从这里给我打了个电话
That's funny. He put a call into me from here about 7:00
是吗
Did he
晚上好
Good evening
伙计们
Folks
好大的风
Pretty good blow
造成了一些损害 我看见了
Did some damage, I see
有几个地方的电源线断了
Power lines are down in a couple of places
- 路况如何？- 还过得去
- How's the road? - Passable
我正在寻找索耶
I'm trying to locate Sawyer
有人见过他吗
Seen him, anybody
你见过索耶吗
Have you seen Sawyer
他之前在这里 因为他从这里给我打过电话
He was here. I know because he called me from here
大约7:00
About 7:00
几分钟后我打了回去
I called back a few minutes later
有人接了电话 是你们中的一员吗
Somebody answered. Was it one of you
我接的
I did
哦 你
Oh, you
你打电话的时候我从楼上下来了
I came down from upstairs when you called
周围没有人 所以我回答了
Nobody was around, so I answered
可能他停在这里打电话
Probably he stopped in to call
然后他继续前进 被困在暴风雨中
Then he went on and got caught in the storm
他现在可能在路上停住了
He's stalled along the road right now, probably
他不在这儿和棕榈林之间
He ain't between here and Palm Grove
他不会给我打电话 除非情况特殊
And he wouldn't have called me unless it was special
看到奥西奥拉兄弟了吗
Seen anything about the Osceola brothers
你有看到吗
Have you
我想这就是他为什么打电话
I figured that was what it was about. His call, I mean
奥西奥拉兄弟
The Osceola brothers
几个印第安人从监狱里逃了出来 我们正在寻找他们
Couple of Indians busted out of jail, and we're looking for them
我在马特库姆贝路找找看
I'll take a run down Matecumbe Way
如果索耶出现 告诉他在这里等一会 我会回来的
If Sawyer shows up, tell him to wait. I'll be back
回头见
See you later
第一次来弗洛里达群岛 您姓
First visit to the Keys, mister
布朗
Brown
这次的暴风雨来得晚 暴风雨通常在初夏
Late in the season for a storm. They usually hit early summer
- 是这样吗？- 一直在钓鱼吗？- 当然
- Is that so? - Been doing any fishing? - Yeah
没有比在这更好的钓鱼地点了
There's no better fishing than on the Keys
待会见
See you later
是他
It's him
索耶
Sawyer
他被谋杀了
He's murdered
我不想说什么 不关我的事
I didn't wanna say anything. It's not my business
但是你说的那些印第安人 他们刚才在这里
But those Indians you were talking about, they were here
奥西奥拉兄弟
The Osceolas
他们在暴风雨期间就在这里 他们几分钟前离开了
They were here during the storm. They left a couple of minutes ago
站住
Stop
站住 否则我就开枪了
Stop or I'll shoot
小心点 别乱动
Watch yourselves. Stay in line
他死了
He's dead
你的印第安人谋杀了索耶
Your Indians murdered Sawyer
你骗了我 坦普尔
You lied to me Temple
你说你没见过奥西奥拉兄弟 你撒谎
You said you hadn't seen the Osceolas. You lied
索耶就在这里 他打电话是因为他找到了奥西奥拉兄弟
Sawyer was here. He called because he'd found the Osceolas
他们想把他的尸体沉入大海
They tried to hide it by sinking his body. .
但是暴风雨把他的尸体冲回了岸
but the storm tore his body loose and threw it up
就在你家门口
Right at your door
这就是罪证所在 就在你家门口
And that's where the crime belongs, at your door
你可能知道他们杀了索耶 我不会放过你
You probably knew they killed Sawyer. I wouldn't put it past you
我会指控你为从犯
And I'm gonna lay charges naming you as accessory
刚才的开枪是怎么了
What was the shooting
奥西奥拉兄弟试图逃跑
The Osceolas tried to get away
我把他俩都杀了
I killed them both
布朗 你叫什么名字
Brown, what's your first name
霍华德
Howard
地址
Address
密尔沃基中央酒店
Hotel Central, Milwaukee
- 你要在这里待多久？- 一周
- How long you gonna be here? - A week
我以前没见过你吗
Haven't I seen you someplace before
我不这么认为
I don't think so
你
You
霍夫・理查德
Hoff. Richard
密尔沃基中央酒店
Hotel Central, Milwaukee
我们都住一起
We're all together
你的全名
Your full name
弗兰克・麦克劳德 没有地址
Frank McCloud. No address
你在这里做什么
What are you doing here
过路
Passing through
你
You
巴斯 巴斯・爱德华 中央酒店 密尔沃基
Bass. Edward Bass. Hotel Central, Milwaukee
我们都住一起
We're all together
到基韦斯特有多远
How far to Key West
大约100英里
About 100 miles
这飓风真大
Some hurricane
以为它会把我们直接吹到海里
Thought it would blow us right out into the ocean
不得不在路上停了几个小时 直到它吹过去
Had to pull up on the road for a couple of hours till it blew over
这飓风真大
That's some hurricane
我明天早上回来
I'll be back in the morning
我们可以吃点东西吗
Can we get something to eat
我们可以吗
Can we
在这儿 各位
In there, everybody
嗨 齐吉
Hi, Ziggy
约翰尼！你好吗
Johnny-boy! How are you
你怎么知道的
What do you know
你让人眼前一新
You're a sight for sore eyes
进来吧
Come on in
嘿 大伙！齐吉
Hey, boys! Ziggy
很高兴再见到你 伙计
It's sure great to see you again, pal
好吧 肚子确实大了
Well, it sure is swell
你长膘了
You put on a little weight
现在等一下
Now wait a minute
- 看看谁在说话！- 哦 当心
- Look who's talking! - Oh, look out
猜猜谁在这里
Say, guess who's here
谁
Who
盖伊 你在哪里
Gaye, where are you
盖伊・唐！别告诉我
Gaye Dawn! Don't tell me
嗯 我...
Well, I'll be...
说吧 她和以前一样漂亮
Say, she's as pretty as ever
约翰尼不在的时候你一直在哪里
Where you been all the time Johnny was away
这附近
Around
如果我知道 我会来找你的
If I'd have known that, I'd have tried to beat Johnny's time
还是齐吉
Same old Ziggy
好了 宝贝
All right, baby
我知道你们很着急 是吧
I know you fellas are in a hurry, huh
鲁
Lou
纸张手感很好
Paper has a good feel
车床工作没问题
Lathe work's okay
肖像很好 行中没有中断
Portrait's good. No breaks in the lines
序列号检查
Serial numbers check out
是的 很自然
Yeah, naturally
背景色没问题
Back color's okay
高级商品
High-class merchandise
嘿 伙计 你打算做什么
Hey, fella, what are you gonna do
不要和他们一起去
Don't go with them
他们会等到你把他们带到古巴 然后杀了你
They'd wait till you get them to Cuba, then kill you
你永远不会离开那条船
You'd never walk off that boat
她是对的 告诉他们你会走 否则他们会伤害你
She's right. Tell them you'll go, or they'll hurt you
然后你到外面时 跑 试着逃跑
Then when you get outside, run. Try to get away
这是你唯一的机会 伙计
It's your only chance, fella
弗兰克 你在想什么
Frank, what are you thinking
你是对的
You were right
你的脑袋认为是这样 但你的整个生命却是另一个样子
Your head says one thing and your whole life says another
你的脑袋总是迷失方向
Your head always loses
在黑暗中 等待一下
Out there in the dark, make a break for it
然后就跑 伙计
Run, fella
是的 这是我脑袋想做的
Yeah, that's what my head says
你要和他们斗吗 弗兰克
You gonna make a fight of it, Frank
我必须这样做
I've got to
多一个罗科 少一个罗科 不值得为之送命
Not that one Rocco more or less makes any difference in this world
我坚持我在楼上说的话
What I said upstairs still goes
我没有改变我的看法
I haven't changed my tune
就是这样
It's just that
我必须这样做
I've got to
好吧 如果你是一名战士 你就无法逃避战斗
Well, if you're a fighter, you can't walk away from a fight
我想这就是答案
That's the answer, I guess
给你 克里
Here you are, Curly
好吧 约翰尼 伙计
Well, Johnny, pal
你什么时候回来
when are you coming back again
现在不会很久了
It won't be long now
有你回来 一切都会像过去一样
With you back again, it'll be like old times
你知道吗
You know something
我敢打赌 两年之内我们将再次实施禁酒令
I bet inside of two years we have Prohibition back again
只是这一次会有所不同 暴徒会团结在一起
Only this time, it'll be different. The mobs will be together
- 不再互相攻击！- 你说的
- No more blasting each other! - You said it
再见 约翰尼
So long, Johnny
再见 齐吉
So long, Ziggy
下次见
See you when
我们走吧
Let's get started
把所有东西都拿下来 士兵的东西也拿下来
Bring everything down. The soldier's stuff too
士兵
Soldier
帮下拉尔夫
Give Ralph a hand
和我们一起去
Coming with us
去还是不去？我很急
Yes or no? I'm in a hurry
图茨 开始折磨他吧
Toots, go to work on him
你赢了
You win
我以为你会改变主意
I thought you'd change your mind last minute
酒店费多少 老头儿
What's the damage, old man
这应该够了
That ought to take care of it
小姐 想一起来吗
Want to come along, sister
好了 小的们
Okay, boys
给我
Give me
我的东西在哪里
Where are my things
我忘了告诉你 你别跟来了
I forgot to tell you. You're not coming
拿着 你可以在这喝醉一个月
Here, on this, you can stay drunk for a month
- 约翰尼 请带上我 - 躲开
- Johnny please take me with you. - Get away
你必须这样带上我 约翰尼 你必须带上我！
You got to, Johnny. You got to! Please
我会戒酒 我会做任何事
I'll stop drinking. I'll do anything
带上我！我爱你！我需要你
Please! I love you! I need you
我会自杀
I'll kill myself
约翰尼 拜托！拜托！
Johnny, please! Please
我会像以前一样对你好
I'll be good to you, like I was before
我不会让你离开我！你得带上我
I won't let you go without me! You've got to take me with you
来吧 士兵
Come on, soldier
走吧 士兵
Get going, soldier
祝你好运 孩子
Good luck, son
是的 祝你好运
Yeah. Good luck
他为什么不跑
Why doesn't he run
快跑 伙计 快跑
Run, fella, run
他为什么不跑
Why doesn't he run
帮我把绳索取下
Will you cast off that bowline
站在船尾准备
Stand by that stern line
好了 启动船了
Okay, let her go
那是他唯一的机会
That was his only chance
他没有没有逃跑
He didn't take it
他应该跑的
He should've run
电话线坏了
The lines are dead
我们航行怎样
How we doing
航线正确
We're right on course
好的 继续保持
Well, keep us that way
你感觉如何 图茨
How you feeling, Toots
我感觉糟透了
I feel awful
你为什么不下船舱
Why don't you go downstairs
那里太热了
It's too hot down there
现在几点了
What time is it
4点多
A little after 4
我们还没走到一半
We're not halfway there yet
- 约翰尼在睡觉？- 是
- Johnny's sleeping? - Yeah
DUMR-022400Z
Dog, Unit, Man, Roger Numeral 022400Z
MRXG-45 失踪的渔船
Man, Roger, X-ray, George Group numera4-5. Missing fishing boat
桑塔纳号正在被带往古巴
Santana is being taken to Cuba
立即对B区进行海上搜索
X-ray. Sea search of area B immediately. X-ray
他们在收音机里谈论的是我们吗
Is us they are talking about on the radio
让他们谈吧
Let them
在这样的雾中 他们都找不到玛丽皇后号
In a fog like this, they couldn't find the Queen Mary
嘿 克里
Hey, Curly
现在几点了
What time is it
4点多
A little after 4
约翰尼
Say, Johnny
我一直在想
I've been thinking
- 关于盖伊 - 她怎么了
- About Gaye. - What about her
你认为不带她来是个好主意吗
Do you think it was such a good idea not to bring her
她很痛苦
She's pretty sore
所以她很痛苦
So she's sore
是的 但她可能会告密
Yeah, but she might squeal
只是出于厌恶
Just for spite
我说她会告密齐吉
On Ziggy, I mean
那又怎样
Well
我明白了
I get it
只需要有一个约翰尼
There's only one Johnny
嘿 你
Hey, you
看看船尾 看看我们有没有挂到什么海带
Look over the stern. See if we picked up any kelp
我感觉糟透了
I feel awful
图茨！帮助
Toots! Help
怎么了
What's the matter
我的枪 它不见了
My gun. It's gone
盖伊
Gaye
图茨
Toots
拉尔夫
Ralph
士兵
Soldier
嘿 士兵
Hey there, soldier
安吉尔 你上去
Angel, you go up
上去！你听到了吗
Go on! Do you hear me
我会被杀
I get killed
你会上去？对吧
You gonna go up there? Are you
没什么好害怕的 图斯杀了他
There's nothing to be afraid of. Toots killed him
那你上去把吧 约翰
Then you go, John
士兵
Soldier
听我说
Listen to me
安吉尔和克里死了
Angel and Curly are dead
只有我和你
There's just me and you
我们将成为合作伙伴 一切都五五分
We'll be partners. Everything will be 50-50
你觉得怎样
What do you say
你听到了吗
Can you hear me
你觉得怎样？成交吗
What do you say? it a deal
我知道你在想什么
I know what you're thinking
你会摆脱我 拿走所有的钱 是吗
You'll get rid of me and take all the money, is that it
是吗
Is it
回答我
Answer me
我告诉你
I'll tell you what
假设我说钱是你的
Suppose I say the money is yours
听着
Here, look
这是你的
It's yours
全是你的 士兵
All yours, soldier
当我们到达古巴时还有更多
Plenty more when we get to Cuba
好的 士兵
Okay, soldier
你听到了吗
You hear me
我会让你发财
I'll make you rich
士兵
Soldier
你还不够大 不能对罗科这样做 我会杀了你
You're not big enough to do this to Rocco. I'll kill you
你永远不能让我就范 永远不能
You'll never bring me in. Never
听着 士兵 我知道
Look, soldier, I know what it is
你以为我有枪 所以你不能相信我
You figure I got a gun, so you can't trust me
对吗
Right
看
Look
看到了吗
See
我正在和你协商
I'm leveling with you
好的 士兵
Okay, soldier
我要出来了
I'm coming out
好的 士兵
Okay, soldier
我没有枪
I got no gun
我要出来了
and I'm coming out
士兵
Soldier
求救 求救
Mayday. Mayday
呼叫NMA
Calling Nan, Mike, Abel
这是ASAN
This is Abel, Sugar, Abel, Nan
呼叫NMA
Calling Nan, Mike, Abel
请讲
Come in, please
这是NMA 请将
This is Nan, Mike, Abel. Go ahead
这是ASAN
This is Abel, Sugar, Abel, Nan
桑塔纳号
The Santana
我的名字是弗兰克・麦克劳德
My name is Frank McCloud
我离基・布克海港12英里 在入港途中
I'm about 12 miles off Boot Key Harbor, on my way in
请讲
Over
你还好吗？你没事儿吧？请讲
Are you all right? Are you all right? Over
是的 但我需要就医 请讲
Yes, but I need medical attention. Over
保持航线
Continue on course
在这个频率上待命
Stand by on this frequency
我在待命
I'm standing by
你能帮我接通拉戈酒店吗？
Will you put me through to the Largo Hotel
待命中
Stand by
齐吉和他的手下进入乔治亚州时 州警察逮捕了他们
State police picked up Ziggy and his men crossing into Georgia
小姐 你必须去辨认他
You'll have to go up and identify him, miss
坦普尔先生 我非常感谢你救了我的命
Mr.Temple, I'm mighty grateful to you for saving my life and all
但是那两个男孩 奥西奥拉兄弟
but those two boys, the Osceolas
我宁愿被杀 也不愿双手沾上无辜者的鲜血
I'd rather been killed than have innocent blood on my hands
我是罪魁祸首
I'm the one to blame
如果他们不信任我 他们就不会来这里 他们还活着
If they hadn't trusted me, they wouldn't have come here and they'd still be alive
即使我们去帮助他们 我们也只能伤害他们
We can't do anything but harm to those people even when we go to help them
不 坦普尔先生 不是你干的
No, Mr.Temple, it wasn't you
这不是警察或任何人
It wasn't the law or anybody
只有约翰尼·罗科
It was only Johnny Rocco
只要他活着 全世界就没有人是安全的
Nobody in the whole world is safe as long as he's alive
我们最好走了 小姐
We better go, miss
拉戈酒店
Hotel Largo
弗兰克
Frank
哦 感谢上帝
Oh, thank God
他没事 爸爸 他要回到我们身边了
He's all right, Dad. He's coming back to us